In the last lecture, we worked on our burger component and made sure that we can output a list of burger
Son dersimizde Bergere bileenimiz zerinde altk ve burger ieriklerinin bir listesini aslnda bir nesne
ingredients, actually a list which started as an object and which we then transform into an array.
olarak balayan ve daha sonra bir dizi haline dntrecek bir liste k yapabildiimizden emin olduk.
Now with that, a first important step was taken, what happens now if we actually have a burger which starts
imdi ilk nemli adm u anda Ciro'ya ayarlanm tm ieriklerle balayan bir burgerimiz
with all ingredients set to 0
varsa ne olurdu.
though. Now we see that but that's perfectly fine,
imdi gryoruz, imdi bu ok iyi.
we have no ingredients to render,
leyecek hibir ieriimiz yok.
we don't get an error because we just have an empty array which we try to render but it would be even
Bo bir diziye sahip olduumuz iin hata yapmyoruz, ancak baz maddeler eklemeye balamanz
better if we could show some message like please start adding ingredients or something like that.
veya byle bir ey yapmaya balamamz gibi bir mesaj gstersek daha da iyi olur.
Now to show something in case we have no ingredients, I need to find out if we got no ingredients. Now
imdi bir ey gstermek iin herhangi bir katk maddesi yok diye reneceiz, nk
transformedIngredients is always going to be an array though,
hibir katk maddesi yoksa, imdi dntrlen maddeler her zaman bir dizi olacak.
just an array of empty arrays
Sadece bir dizi bo dizi.
in the end.
Sonunda.
But that is something which is kind of hard to check for us,
Ancak bize bir eyleri kontrol etmesi zor bir ey veri.
so how can we find out if we got ingredients or not? We can reduce the transformedIngredients array,
Peki, ierdiklerimiz var m yoksa olmadn nasl bilebiliriz? Dntrlen maddeler dizisini azaltabiliriz.
for now let's simply console log it so that we get an idea about how it looks like. For now save this,
u an iin nasl grndne dair bir fikir edinebileceiz, bu hastaln ktmz maddeler diziliminden kurtulduumuz hakknda
this is our ingredients array which we output and of course it's a couple of empty arrays and hence
bir fikir edineceiz ve elbette birka bo diziler ve bu nedenle ie yaramyor veya almyor .
doesn't work or it does work
imdilik, logoyu konsolla ele alalm, bylece
but it doesn't display anything.
Ama hibir ey gstermiyor.
So checking the length won't do the trick because the length is four,
Uzunluu kontrol etmek, hile yapmaz nk uzunluu drttr.
it's these inner arrays which are interesting to us. What we can do is we can simply flatten this array
Bize ilgin olan bu i diziler, yapabildiimiz ey bu i dizilerin deerlerini
to make sure we pull out the values of these inner arrays and trade one array only which contains all
karmamz ve yalnzca bu deerleri ieren bir dizi ticaretini salamak iin bu diziyi
these values,
dzletirmeniz olabilir.
we can do that by adding reduce to our transformedIngredients logic here, reduce is a built-in array function
Bunu, dntrlm ieriklerimize indirgemeyi ekleyerek yapabiliriz mant, bir diziyi baka bir ey haline
which allows us to transform an array into something else.
dntrmemizi salayan her ilevi azaltr.
It takes a function as an input and this function receives two arguments passed in automatically by
Bir girdi olarak bir ilev alr ve bu ilev, otomatik olarak javascript tarafndan geirilen iki
javascript,
bamsz deiken alr.
the previous value and the current value. The reduce method does not only accept these callback here
Azaltma metodunun nceki deeri ve imdiki deer sadece cana karlk gelen Colback'i burada kabul etmez; burada,
which is executed on every element in this array we return here,
kargaann her elementinde idam edilir, burada dndrrz.
it also accepts an initial value,
Ayrca bir balang deeri kabul eder.
let's say an empty array.
Bo bir dizi diyelim.
So the initial value of the reduced value
Yani indirgenmi deerin balang deeri.
now of course you want to adjust this reduced value by returning something
imdilik elbette bir ey dndrerek bu dk deeri ayarlamak istiyorsunuz.
and it will then loop through all the elements and simply add them to the initial values step by step.
Ve daha sonra tm eler arasnda dolap basite balang deerlerine adm adm ekler.
So here I want to return the updated values starting with the initial one is then stored in the first argument
Dolaysyla, balangtaki deerlerden balayarak gncellenmi deerleri dndrmek isterseniz, burada her ilmekte
which we receive in each loop here.
aldmz ilk argman depolanr.
So array this
Bu yzden dizin.
argument is the always updated root array which I want to return in the end.
Argmanm, sonunda dnmek istediim her zaman gncellenmi rota.
So I will simply concat something to that, concat(el), this will simply take the given element through
Dolaysyla basite bu baa bir ey yakalayamayacam. Bu, dndrdm ve bu
which we're looping and add it to this array.
diziye eklediimiz belirli eyi alacaktr.
Now if we save this, we get an empty array
imdi bunu kurtarrsak bo bir dizi alrz.
and if I reintroduce an ingredient like two cheese pieces, we get an array with two objects and the fact
Ve iki peynir paras gibi yeniden yaynlandm tekrar duyurursak, iki nesne ieren bir dizi elde ederiz ve
that these objects look strange simply is related to the fact that these are jsx elements handled
bu nesnelerin garip grnmesi, bunlarn Jae'nin tepki verdii X eleri olduu
by react,
gereiyle ilgilidir.
it is of type cheese though, as you can see.
Geri grebildiiniz kadaryla.
So this is how we now flattened the array
imdi diziyi dzletirdik.
and if this is unclear, I strongly recommend checking out the documentation of this default javascript
Ve eer bu belirsizse, harita ve azaltmak gibi bu varsaylan javascript
array functions like map and reduce.
dizi ilevlerinin belgelerini kontrol etmenizi neririm.
So with that, we got an array which is either empty or contains the jsx elements
Bu durumda bo olan veya X elerini ieren bir dizi var.
and since it might be empty, we can simply check if transformedIngredients length is equal to zero,
Ve bo olabileceinden, dntrlm bileenlerin uzunluu sfra eit olup olmadn basite kontrol edebiliriz.
if that's the case then I want to output a paragraph where I say we start adding elements.
Durum buysa, eleri eklemeye baladm diyelim bir paragraf k istiyorum.
I will therefore convert
Bu nedenle sz syleyeceim.
this constant transformedIngredients to a variable, in ES6
Bu, iOS 6'daki bir deikene sabit bir bileen.
we use let for this.
Bunu bunun iin kullanrz.
And then here, I will set transformedIngredients equal to a paragraph where I will simply say please
Ve sonra buraya, dntrlm bileenleri bir paragrafa eit olarak ayarlayacam ve burada unu
start adding ingredients, like this
syleyeceim; byle maddeler eklemeye ltfen balayn.
and we still output transformedIngredients down there.
Ve biz hala fakir retim transferi ve ierikler var.
Save the file and update the burger builder to have no cheese anymore
Dosyay kaydedin ve artk peynir olmamak iin burgeri Bolar' gncelleyin.
and now if you save that too, you should simply start adding ingredients and of course this should
Ve imdi bu sray kaydettiyseniz, sadece katk maddeleri eklemeye balamalsnz ve elbette bu
also stick
da yapmaldr.
no matter what your viewport is.
Bak as ne olursa olsun.
That is another important step.
Bu nemli bir adm daha.
Now the next step is to start adding these controls to let the user add and remove ingredients.
imdi bir sonraki adm, kullancya katk maddeleri ekleyip karmak iin bu denetimleri eklemeye balamaktr.